擎天柱 说了你也不信
Optimus, you are not going to believe this.
我刚刚完成了对霸天虎战舰的精确定位
I just pinpointed the location of the Decepticon warship.
他们的隐身技术被你破解了吗？
How did you penetrate their cloaking technology?
我没破解
I didn't.
我是在试验各种频段波长时 偶然发现的
I was experimenting the variable frequency wavelengths when I stumbled upon it.
而且 他们的飞船一定受到了某种电磁破坏
Even still, their ship must be experiencing some kind of electromagnetic breach.
威震天死了 趁他们疏于防范…
With Megatron deceased and the element of surprise...
我们可以来个当头一棒
We can cause some serious damage.
同一个频率上 还发现了汽车人紧急信标
Also in the same frequency, an Autobot emergency beacon.
霸天虎的事先放一放 很可能有汽车人遇难
The Decepticons can wait, there maybe Autobots in distress.
救护车 带上医疗包
Rachet, bring your medical kit.
飞船迫降 看来已经坠毁几百年了
A crash landing, buried here for centuries.
如果他们是在休眠模式下航行 或许还有幸存者
If they traveled in stasis mode, there may be survivors.
擎天柱 这些汽车人并不是死于飞船失事
Optimus, these Autobots didn't perish in the crash.
他们的症状…像是感染了病毒
They are displaying the effects of a virus.
这是艘瘟船
This is a plague ship.
什么都别碰！
Don't touch anything.
病毒可能还有活性
The virus could still be active.
不！
No!
是灰死病
Cybonic plague.
（Cybonic plague影射Bubonic plague，即黑死病）
It's only contagious if contact is made with the infected energeon.
只有在接触被感染能量时才会被传染
汽车人飞船里怎么会有瘟疫呢？
What was a plague doing in an Autobot spaceship?
飞船上有被感染的乘客
Its passengers were infected.
塞博特恩大战时期 这种病毒夺去了无数生命
The virus wiped out millions on Cybertron during the great war.
灰死病是霸天虎生物战争计划的产物
Cybonic plague was engineered in the Decepticons' Biological Warfare Program...
由威震天亲自研发
by Megatron himself.
你…有解药 是吧？
You have a cure, don't you?
无药可救…
No cure...
擎天柱 拜托 保存一点体力吧
Optimus, please, save your strength.
威震天能制造病毒 怎么会不造解药？
Would Megatron create a disease without having a cure?
我是说 万一他不小心感染了怎么办？
I mean what if he caught it by accident?
可我们没法拷问威震天了 杰克
It's not like we can ask Megatron, Jack.
他已经上西天了
He's pushing up lugnuts.
但是 没准可以查询霸天虎的数据库
But we might be able to access the Decepticon database.
目前 我们还掌握着他们战舰的位置
For the moment, we still have a fix on their warship's location.
大黄蜂 跟我走
Bumblebee, come with.
阿尔茜 尽快吧
Arcee, quickly.
我们从实验室开始找
Let's start with the lab.
我进入他们的网络了
I'm in the network.
救护车…
Rachet...
你有没有…
Were you...
被感染？没有
Infected? No.
数据真在这里吗 我没找到
If it's here, I don't see it.
你能确定吗 阿尔茜？
Are you certain, Arcee?
我搜索了所有文件 没找到
I searched every file, nothing.
那就再找一遍！你肯定有遗漏！
Well, search again! Clearly you missed something!
整个数据库我都扫描遍了！
I scanned the entire database.
你用过冗余量子算法吗？
Did you use a redundant quantum algorithm?
别用那些名词吓唬我
Don't tell me how to research.
你以为只有你自己关心擎天柱吗？
You think you are the only one who cares about Optimus?
怎么回事？
What is it?
怎么了？出什么事了？
What is it? What's going on?
是威震天
It's Megatron.
他还…活着
He's alive.
什么？
What?
那不可能！
That's not possible!
可我看见的确实是他
But I'm staring right at him.
好消息是
Good news is
威震天没有回应我的目光
Megatron isn't exactly staring back.
威震天？
Megatron?
他不行了 全靠生命维持系统撑着
He's critical, hooked up to life support.
该把他一劳永逸地解决掉了
Time to finish this once and for all.
慢着！别动手！
Wait! Don't!
给我个好理由 快说！
One good reason, fast!
威震天或许是救活擎天柱的唯一希望
Megatron may be Optimus's only hope for survival.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
他的脑电波还有活动吗？
Does he display brainwave activity?
很强烈 他的病态思维仍在运转
Spiking hard, his sick mind still at work.
太好了！如果真的有解药 威震天可能是唯一知道底细的人
Perfect. If a cure exists, Megatron maybe the only one who knows it.
你们必须进入他的大脑 找到解药！
You must enter his brain and find it.
进入威震天的大脑？
Enter Megatron's brain?
救护车 你是不是疯了？
Rachet, are you out of your fragging mind?
霸天虎实验室应该有所需的全部设备 你可以执行大脑皮层通灵驳接
The Decepticon laboratory should contain all the equipment you need for a cortical psychic patch.
不行 你以前有没有执行过这套程序？
No way. Have you ever even performed the procedure?
没有 但我仔细研究过理论资料…
No. But I have thoroughly studied the theoretical literature...
它是霸天虎发明的 但被汽车人明令禁止
invented by Decepticons, outlawed by Autobots.
哇 我们用环陆桥把威震天运走 时间不是会充裕一点吗？
Whoa, can't we just haul Megatron through the GroundBridge, buy us some time to figure this out?
擎天柱可没有那么充裕的时间！
Time is one thing that Optimus does not have!
你们俩必须有人试一下！
One of you must try this！
我绝不容许在威震天归西之前 就要给擎天柱送终！
I will not allow Optimus to pass knowing that Megatron will outlive him!
救护车 我愿意为擎天柱拼命 无论何时何地
Ratchet, I would lay down my life for Optimus, anytime, anywhere.
可要说灵魂出窍…
But a mind-body split...
你要去吗？
You will?
你有…把握吗 大黄蜂？
Are you... sure, Bumblebee?
小蜂是我们最棒的侦察兵
Bee's the best scout there is.
电磁防护罩为什么还没修好？
Why has the elctromagnetic shielding not been repaired?
舰员正在尽全力抢修 陛下…
The crews are working as quickly as they can, Lord...
我们的航迹暴露了！
We are leaking a trail!
汽车人只要访问正确的频段波长 就能获得我们的准确位置
All the Autobots need do to pinpoint our position is to access the correct frequency wavelength.
动作再快点！
Accelerate your efforts!
遵命 红蜘蛛陛下
Yes, Lord Starscream.
医官报到
Doctor in the house.
啊 击倒 病人今天状况如何？
Ah, Knock Out, and how is the patient doing today?
老样子…
Same old...
保持这种植物人状态 真是让他无地自容
An inglorious fate that he should remain in this vegetative state...
正相反 威震天的身体也许成了废铁
On the contrary, Megatron's body may be scrap metal
但他的思维还是很活跃的
but his mind is still percolating.
你自己知道就行了！
Keep that to yourself!
那该死的声波好像有千里眼和顺风耳
That blasted Soundwave sees and hears everything.
他是霸天虎的耳目嘛
The eyes and ears of the Decepticons.
只要他们的主子一天不醒 他们就是群无头苍蝇
Well, as long as their master remains in limbo, so does their cause.
霸天虎急需一位强悍的 警醒的领袖
The Decepticons deserve a strong, alert leader.
这位领袖也需要一个忠诚的副官
One who would require a loyal second-in-command.
要想坐上副官的位置 必须干得漂亮点 才能让那个“耳目”闭嘴
Hmhmhm, a candidate would need to earn that post by making a strong case to said eyes and ears.
需要发发慈悲吗 红蜘蛛陛下？
A case for showing mercy, Lord Starscream?
你敬我一尺 我敬你一丈
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
救护车 我们准备好了
Ratchet, we are ready.
启动大脑皮层通灵驳接
Initiate cortical psychic patch.
通讯下行链路激活
Communications downlink activated.
这样我们就能利用大黄蜂的视觉和听觉
This will allow us to see and hear everything Bumblebee does
进入威震天的潜意识
while within Megatron's subconscious mind.
哇 那是什么地方？
Whoa, where is that?
小蜂说那儿像是卡隆 霸天虎在塞博特恩上的首都
Bee says it looks like Kaon, the Decepticon Capital back on Cybertron.
老救 大哥的情况很差
Ratch, Optimus's vitals.
我知道
I know.
快点 大黄蜂
Quickly, Bumblebee.
我知道那是个陌生环境
I know you are in unknown territory
但你必须在威震天的意识里 找到信息的大致储存位置
but you must figure out where information might be filed in Megatron's mind.
大黄蜂 那不是擎天柱
Bumblebee, that is not Optimus
只是威震天的思维幻像
but a figment of Megatron's mind.
他看不见 也听不到你
It cannot see or hear you.
哈哈 擎天柱！
Mmmmhahaha, Optimus Prime!
你的汽车人部队战败了
Your Autobot armies are defeated.
向你的新主人鞠躬吧
Bow before your new master.
我决不低头 威震天
Never, Megatron.
不是你死 就是我亡
One shall stand, one shall fall.
那就来吧
So be it.
这事我可没见过
That never happened.
这不是记忆
It's not a memory.
我们看见的卡隆 是威震天在他的黑暗梦境里重建的
We're seeing Kaon as Megatron has recreated it in his darkest dreams.
威震天 你的恶行到此为止吧
Megatron, your treachery ends here.
汽车人侦察兵
The Autobot scout.
胆敢擅闯我的领地 我让你灰飞烟灭！
The punishment for trespassing in my domain is your destruction!
这怎么可能？
How can this be?
威震天碰不到小蜂吗？
Megatron can't touch Bee?
因为他不是威震天的意识产物
Because he's not a creation of Megatron's mind
大黄蜂对他的物理攻击免疫
Bumblebee is immune to his physical attack.
你没有穿戴相移盔甲
You are not wearing phase displacement armor.
你的眼睛可以追踪我的动作 说明你不是全息图像
Your eyes track my movements, so you are not a hologram.
我也不相信灵魂论
And I do not believe in spirits.
快告诉我 侦察兵 你是什么东西？
So tell me, scout, what are you?
威震天！
Megatron!
啊哦 特邀嘉宾来了
Uho, special guest stars.
这可不太妙
This is not good.
你是真实的 他们不是！
You are real. They were not!
大脑皮层通灵驳接
Hehehe, a cortical psychic patch.
真想不到啊
How unexpected.
我们扰乱了威震天的无意识状态
We've stirred Megatron from his oblivion.
他开始恢复自我意识了！
He's becoming self-aware.
如果这是我的潜意识
If this is my subconscious
你在我的脑子里干什么？
what are you doing inside my head?
加油 小蜂 你到底在干嘛？
Come on, Bee. What are you doing in there?
击倒 麻烦你向声波讲一下 专家的治疗意见
Knock Out, if you would be so kind as to provide your expert medical opinion to Soundwave
以便记录在案
for the historical record.
简单来说 如果没有外力协助 威震天会永远保持这种假死状态
Simply put, unaided, Megatron could remain in this deadless slumber forever.
我们的主人不会希望自己成为这个样子
Our master would not have wanted to be seen this way.
眼看着他的灵魂被禁锢 我们却无所事事 这不公平
To stand idly by while he remains captive in his own body, is not just.
脑电波的活动不能证明他拥有意识 只是陷入了无穷的梦境
Brainwave activity, not evidence of consciousness, but merely of an endless dream
威震天或许永远都无法醒过来
from which Megatron may never wake.
声波 我们必须面对现实
Soundwave, we must face reality.
我们已经痛失威震天
Megatron is lost to us.
唯一体面的选择 就是让他解脱
The only honorable option, would be to show him mercy.
只是拨动一个开关而已
A simple throw off the switch.
迅速 没有痛苦 充满怜悯
Quick, painless, compassionate.
救护车 你听到了吗？
Ratchet, are you hearing this?
如果威震天死了
If Megatron perishes
大黄蜂的意识就会和他的身体分离 永远分离
Bumblebee's mind will remain separated from his body, forever.
那我们岂不要同时失去大黄蜂和擎天柱？
We'll lose Bumblebee and Optimus?
你能进入我的意识的唯一办法 就是通过大脑皮层通灵驳接
The only way you could have entered my mind, is via cortical psychic patch.
但是还有问题
But the question remains...
我到底是怎么了？
What happened to me?
太空桥爆炸
The SpaceBridge explosion.
另外 如果你能进入我的大脑 就说明我还没彻底死亡
And yet if, if you're in my head, I am not one with the Allspark.
告诉我 侦察兵 我是不是还活着？
So tell me, scout, do I still function?
大黄蜂 我们没时间了！
Bumblebee, we are out of time!
灰死病？
Cybonic plague?
除了我自己 还有人被…感染了？
Somebody beside myself is, is unwell?
擎天柱！
Optimus!
真是讽刺！
Such irony!
经历了连年的战争
That after ages of endless battle
伟大的擎天柱居然在远古时代的 简单病毒面前败下阵来！
the mighty Optimus Prime is fell by a simple virus from the distant past!
你凭什么以为 我会出手拯救我的老对头？
And what makes you think I would save the life of my oldest enemy?
威震天 你的恶行…
Megatron, your treachery is...
噢 那么我最想要的是什么呢 侦察兵？
Oh, and just what is it that I want most, scout?
你没看到吗 擎天柱可以被我亲手杀死
Haha, did you not see, I do slay Optimus by my own hand
我随心所欲 想杀就杀！
at will, whenever I desire!
小蜂告诉威震天 如果他让病毒毁掉擎天柱的话
Bee told Megatron if he lets the plague virus destroy the real Optimus
他就再也没机会亲自动手了
Megatron will never get the chance to do it himself.
聪明！
Smart!
变态！
Twisted!
声波 我可不可以认为 你用沉默来表示认同击倒的专业见解？
Soundwave, do I take your silence to mean you concur with Knock Out's medical expertise?
要么开口 要么永远闭上你的臭嘴
Speak now, or forever hold your peace.
说啊…
Going.
Going...
糟了！
Scrap!
这么多恩恩怨怨都走过来了 如果不能亲眼看到擎天柱熄灭火种的话…
After our deep history together, to not watch the spark end from Optimus's eyes with my very own...
干得好 侦察兵
Well-played, scout.
这就是你要找的解药配方
The chemical formula for the cure you seek.
我并不指望你能读懂
Not that I expect you to know how to read it.
现在不行
Not yet.
既然你提议 让我亲手终结擎天柱的生命
And how am I to accomplish terminating Optimus as you proposed
可我怎么能摆脱这个无限循环的白日梦呢？
while I'm traped here in a perpetual day-dream?
只要你帮我逃出这个监狱 就可以得到解药
Once you release me from this prison, you will have the cure.
快点 快点！
Come on, come on.
你必须保证让我复原 否则\N擎天柱只能变灰 然后死掉
You must guarantee my recovery, or Optimus fades to gunmetal grey.
我说的是真正的擎天柱
The REAL Optimus.
阿尔茜 配方已经到手
Arcee, we have the formula.
断开大黄蜂的驳接 快！
Disconnect Bumblebee, now!
你们在监视 你骗了我！
You were watching, you tricked me!
不！带我一起走！带我走…
No, take me with you! Take me! Take me! Take me!
快点啊 小蜂！
Hurry, Bee.
怎么…
What in...
入侵者！
Intruders!
让我来吧！
Allow me!
唉 结局在所难免
Huh, it was the inevitable outcome.
当然了 不该让威震天牺牲在汽车人的手里
Uhhh... of course it would be wrong to allow Megatron to perish by an Autobot's hand
击倒
Knock Out.
就这样 稳住
That's it. Steady.
请各位把对英雄的欢呼留给我的医师 还有我的侦察兵
Please, reserve the hero's welcome for my physician, and my scout.
- 没事了\N- 是啊！
- Alright.\N- Yes!
病人今天的情况如何？
And how is the patient doing today?
这话问得好
Funny, you should ask.
不清楚汽车人在他脑子里动了什么手脚
Not sure what the Bots did in there.
但是威震天的脑电波已经归零了
But Megatron's registering zero brainwave activity.
嗯 说明什么？
Mmm, meaning?
表面来看他很稳定 但现在
Physically he is stable, but now
他的…灵魂消失了
there is no one home.
我出来了
I'm out.
或许该说…进来了！
Or should I say, IN!